在上一集里
Previously on Transformers: Prime...
飞船迫降 看来已经坠毁几百年了
A crash landing, buried here for centuries.
这些汽车人并不是死于飞船失事
These Autobots didn't perish in the crash.
他们的症状…像是感染了病毒
They are displaying the effects of a virus.
如果真的有解药 威震天可能是唯一知道底细的人
If a cure exists, Megatron maybe the only one who knows it.
你们必须进入他的大脑 找到解药！
You must enter his brain and find it.
你在我的脑子里干什么？
What are you doing inside my head?
配方已经到手 断开大黄蜂的驳接 快！
We have the formula, disconnect Bumblebee, now!
不！带我一起走！
No, take me!
我出来了
I'm out! Hahahahahaha...
眼睛看着光 好 好
Follow the light. Good, good.
我建议你不要做剧烈运动 擎天柱
I wouldn't advice anything strenuous, Optimus
尽管目前看来 你的系统已经从灰死病的侵蚀中完全恢复了
but it appears that your systems have fully recovered from the Cybonic plague.
幸好有你高明的医术 老朋友
Thanks to your medical expertise, old friend.
幸好有你的侦察兵 单枪匹马 深入虎穴找到解药
It was your scout who braved unknown territory to locate the cure.
幸好威震天还活着
Lucky for us Megatron was still alive.
没错 的确很走运
Yea, I actually said that.
重要的是 你的病情有所好转 擎天柱
What matters is that you are on the mend, Optimus
威震天现在…
while Megatron...
小蜂说得对 我很想手刃威震天
Bee's right, 'did my best to finish Megatron's story.
可当时来不及看他咽下最后一口气
Just couldn't stick around long enough to see how it ended.
擎天柱早晚会发现你心怀鬼胎 侦察兵
It is a matter of time before Optimus discovers all is not right with you, scout.
我必须取回我的身体
I must reclaim my body
也就是说 眼下我要完完全全地控制你的身体！
which means taking complete and total control of yours.
塞博特恩式篮球比赛
Basketball by way of Cybertron.
比赛正式开始！
Let the games begin!
漂亮！小隔加油！
Yeah, go Bulk!
来吧 我们三局两胜！
Come on, best two out of three.
小蜂 现在后防空虚！
Bee, you are in the clear!
扣篮啊 小蜂！
Dunk it, Bee!
大黄蜂 小心持球违例！
Bumblebee, quit hugging the ball!
恶意犯规！
Ngrr, flagrant foul!
更像是塞博特恩躲避球比赛
Dodge Ball by way of Cybertron.
小蜂 篮筐在那边
Bee, hoop's over there.
小蜂 你没事吧？
Bee, you OK?
好吧 那就五局三胜
Yea, three out of five.
如果我想回到自己的身体里去
If I am to return my body
必须先恢复身体的各项功能
I must first restore its functionality.
我当初是如何逃过一劫的？
How did I escape annihilation?
对了 是黑暗能量！
Of course, Dark Energon!
红蜘蛛！
Starscream!
当当当 有人在里面吗？
Knock, knock. Is anyone in there?
没有？那好吧…
No. Oh well...
看来我拥有唯一一个
Seems I possess the only thing
能让你从病榻上重新站起来的东西
that would allow you to rise off that slab and walk again.
最最亲爱的威震天…
My dearest Megatron...
这星球上仅存的碎片
The only scrap left on this planet
正是从你的火种室里拔出来的
plucked from your very spark chamber.
但它并不能恢复你的意识
But it cannot restore your mind.
霸天虎需要的是首领
The Decepticons need a leader
不是高高在上的废铁
not a decorative centerpiece.
我会向他们证明 只有我才配继承你的王位
And I will convince them that I am the true heir to your throne
我要勾画一副宏伟蓝图…
with a plan so epic...
连强大的威震天 也构思不出的那种蓝图？
Not even the mighty Megatron could've conceived it?
呃 我就是这么想的 击倒
Eh, that was the idea, Knock Out.
你过来多久了？
How long have you been there?
很久了
Long enough.
请叫我击倒指挥官
And it's Commander Knock Out to you
永恒的王者 红蜘蛛陛下
once and future Lord Starscream.
拉夫？已经上课了
Raf? Class is starting.
大黄蜂没来送我上学
Bumblebee never picked me up for school
他的通讯链也关了
and his comlink is off again.
你知道他在哪里么？
Any idea where he is?
对 继续 侦察兵 服从我的意志！
Yes, go on scout, obey my will!
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee!
那东西我还有用呐！
I needed that!
你脑子里究竟在想什么？
What has got into you?
你看见威震天了？
You are seeing Megatron's face?
大黄蜂说 他总能看见断断续续的影像
Bumblebee's complaining of intermittent visions.
可以说是种梦魇
Waking nightmares, if you will.
但你给小蜂做全面检查时 说他很健康
But, you said Bee was fine when you checked him over.
身体很健康
Physically
但一些不堪回首的经历 似乎对他的心理造成了暂时影响
but the experience he endured seems to be having a temporary effect on his psychy.
这次诱导性休眠 可以强行停止并恢复大黄蜂的意识
This induced power down should force Bumblebee's mind to rest and recover.
擎天柱 你最近发现穿草裙的霸天虎了吗？
Prime, you spot any Decepticons wearing hula skirt lately?
没发现 福勒探员 又怎么了？
No, Special Agent Fowler. Why?
我以为你有虎子的线索呢
Coz I was hoping you have a lead on the Cons
他们破坏了夏威夷考艾岛的海军气象台
that busted into the Kauai Naval Observatory.
那里看起来像是被军队强拆了一样
Place look like it was hit by an army of wrecking balls.
霸天虎干嘛要进攻一个气象台？
Why would Cons break into an Observatory?
“霍伊克・尼哥高西安”这个名字耳熟么？
Does the Heuck Nigoghossian ring any bells?
是那个太空望远镜！
The space telescope!
昨晚 它的主镜头被盗了
As of last night missing its primary lens.
很难猜测红蜘蛛有什么意图
It's difficult to guess Starscream's intent
我们并不知道镜头的下落
without knowing where the lens has been taken.
好在那个镜头有跟踪装置
Good thing's the lens has a tracking device.
北极？太好了！
The Arctic? Great!
又可以体验火种被冻僵的感觉了
Another chance to freeze our sparkplugs off.
是ND-7级别的区域 那儿的能量矿面积最大 但无法开采
Hew... That's a ND-7 class, biggest unminable energon deposit there is.
除非红蜘蛛能想办法让冰面融化
Unminable until Starscream melt his way down to it.
那个镜头可以派上用场
With the help of the lens.
融化那片大冰川 会使海平面上升 淹没沿海城市
Melting a glacier that size would cause sea levels to rise and demolish coastal cities.
让红蜘蛛陛下赐予的甘露…降临吧
Let the rain of Lord Starscream... begin.
我风驰电掣般冲过终点线
So I blow pass the finish line.
然后另一个姐姐问我 为何这么擅长赛车
Then my other sister Plaura asked how I got so good at racing games.
我就说 我认识一个非常懂车的家伙
And I told her I know a guy who knows cars.
拉斐尔 恐怕大黄蜂听不见你说话 他正处于休眠模式
Raphael, I'm afraid Bumblebee can't hear you in power-down mode.
太晚了 要不然 我先送你回家吧？
It's getting late. Why don't I bridge you home to your family?
我跟小蜂说过 我要留下 他也是我的家人
Because I told Bee I'd stay. He's family, too.
别扯了 你们根本不是同一个物种
Don't be ridiculous. You are not even the same species.
那叫“亲戚”
That's being related.
“亲戚”跟“家人”是两回事 我拿给你看
It's not the same thing. I'll show you.
这是我的全家福照片
This is my family.
嗯 嗯 是的 很好
Hm, hm. Yes, very nice.
是个大家庭
Very large.
有时即使我大喊大叫 也没人理我
Sometimes I can shout and no one hears me.
是是是…
Yes, yes, yes, yes...
但是大黄蜂总会听我说话
But Bumblebee always listens.
我也能理解他的滴滴声
And I can understand him.
不知为什么 我全能听懂
I'm not sure why, but I do.
和上次的极地旅行相比 变化很大
A lot different than our last polar visit.
感觉像是夏天
Feels like summer.
看 问题出在那儿
Here, that's a bad thing.
汽车人 还记得在乱魔城的那次迂回进攻吗？
Autobots, remember the end run on Polyhex?
（Polyhex 乱魔城 塞博特恩环轨行省之一 曾是卫星和网络指挥中心 内战中被霸天虎攻占 建有众多熔炼池和角斗场）
拉斐尔 我要去仓库找些零件来修理这个
Raphael, I'm going to the supply vol to see if I can find parts to repair this.
你应该明白我的意思吧？
You know what that means?
（Polyhex 乱魔城 塞博特恩环轨行省之一 曾是卫星和网络指挥中心 内战中被霸天虎攻占 建有众多熔炼池和角斗场）
"Don't touch anything."
“什么都别碰”
先看看这台新手提电脑 我存钱要买的 小蜂
Wait til I see this new laptop I'm saving up for, Bee.
小蜂？
Bee?
大黄蜂 等等！
Bumblebee, wait!
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee!
你碰什么了？
What did you do?
什么也没碰 大黄蜂是自己站起来的…
Nothing, Bumblebee just got up and...
他明明处于休眠模式！
He was in power-down.
他这是要去哪儿？
Where does he think he's off to?
它在哪儿？在哪儿？
Where is it? Where?
这些坐标指向我们上次 遭遇威震天不死大军的地方
These are the coordinates for the site of our previous battle with Megatron's undead.
我们是不是该通知擎天柱？
Maybe we should call Optimus?
擎天柱正忙着解决极地冰盖融化的事
Optimus is busy preventing a polar ice cap from melting.
我们得自己处理了
We need to handle this on our own.
大黄蜂？你干什么去了？
Bumblebee? What have you been doing?
黑暗能量？
Dark Energon?
小蜂 你在干什么！
Bee, what are you doing?
大黄蜂 拜托！我知道你的意识还在！
Bumblebee, please! I know you are in there!
你必须和控制你意识的东西做斗争！
You have to fight whatever is making you do this!
救护车 你没事吧？
Ratchet, are you OK?
我没事 问题在于 大黄蜂怎么了？
I'm fine. More importantly, is bumblebee?
我担心他在威震天的意识里逗留太久
I fear the time spent in Megatron's mindscape
导致他的思维越来越像霸天虎
is causing him to think like a Decepticon.
小蜂才不是虎子呢！
Bee's not a Con!
我同意 但我们必须弄清楚
Agreed, but we need to find out exactly
大黄蜂拿着那个碎片要做什么
what Bumblebee intends to do with that shard.
唯一一个了解黑暗能量的人
The only one who knew of the Dark Energon
就是威震天
was Megatron.
大黄蜂拥有威震天的记忆？
Bumblebee has Megatron's memories?
可能更糟 威震天在控制大黄蜂的思想
Worse, Megatron is occupying Bumblebee's mind.
什么？
What?
我怎么那么蠢！
How could I've been such a fool!
大脑皮层通灵驳接是个交互式的过程
The cortical psychic patch acted as a two-way condulet.
当大黄蜂的意识回归身体时
When Bumblebee returned to his own mind
威震天也紧跟其后
Megatron followed.
而现在大黄蜂――
And now Bumblebee--
应该说威震天 已经把自己传送到擎天柱的位置附近
Megatron has bridged to nearly the same coordinates Optimus used.
你留在这里
Stay here.
不 大黄蜂需要我！
No. Bumblebee needs me!
他的确需要你
Of course he does.
是的！计划终于按部就班地实施了！
Yes! I love when a plan comes together!
汽车人！
Autobots!
劳驾 红蜘蛛陛下 请给你的副官一次立功的机会
Please, Lord Starscream. Allow your second-in-command the honor.
打击 消灭他们！
Breakdown, total them!
霸天虎的战舰！
The Decepticon warship!
这是大黄蜂干的吗？
Did Bumblebee do this?
恐怕威震天的意识占了上风
I fear Megatron's mind is dominant.
而且很明显 他来这里只有一个目的――
And clearly he came here for one purpose--
用黑暗能量来修复自己的身体
to use the Dark Energon to resurrect his own body.
不 大黄蜂不会让他得逞的！
No. Bumblebee won't let him.
刚才在基地 他就没让威震天伤害我
Like he didn't let Megatron hurt me back at base.
希望你是对的
I hope you're right.
救护车 别伤害大黄蜂！
Ratchet, don't hurt Bumblebee!
那不是大黄蜂！
That's not Bumblebee!
大黄蜂 住手！
Bumblebee, no!
想想你是谁 想想我！
Remember who you are, remember me!
我知道无论如何 你都会听我说话的！
I know you'll always listen to me, no matter what!
没错 小蜂 是我啊！
That's right, Bee. It's me!
怎么会这样！
Unbelievable!
永别了 威震天！
Farewell, Megatron!
大黄蜂！
Bumblebee!
大黄蜂再也听不到你说话了！
Bumblebee can't hear you anymore!
虽然我很想让你离开大黄蜂的身体
As mush as I want you to leave Bumblebee's body
可我决不让你回到自己的躯壳！
I can't let you go back to your own!
霸天虎们 你们至高无上的主人已经回来了！
Decepticons, your rightful lord and master has returned!
把这些虫子消灭掉！
Finish these pests!
有个死刑 我要去亲手执行
I have my own extermination to perform.
把你冻成冰块怎么样？
How about I put you on ice?
汽车人是不是…缺乏人手？
Don't the Bots seem... understaff?
一个顾前不顾后的副官 我要他何用！
Uhhh... What good is a second-in-command who fails to watch the rear!
给我滚开！
Get out of my way!
不！！
No!!
擎天柱！
Optimus!
威震天犯下的最大的错误
Megatron's greatest mistake
就是放你一条生路 擎天柱！
was ever allowing you to live, Prime!
威震天…
Megatron...
他回来了
He's back.
威震天…陛下 您…这…您痊愈了！
Lord... Megatron, you... are... you are healed!
感谢火种源 奇迹发生了！
Praise the Allspark, it is a miracle!
喔 奇迹会发生的 红蜘蛛
Oh, it will be a miracle, alright, Starscream.
这要看你能不能逃过我的惩罚！
if you survive what I have planned for you!
可那些汽车人…还有擎天柱！您看 就在您脚下！
But the Autobots! Optimus! Right there, waiting for you!
我犯下了大错吗？其实有很多
My greatest mistake? I've made a few.
但有一种错误 我绝不会再犯！
But there is one I do not intend to make again!
不 主人 不！！！
No, master, nooooo...
救护车 我们需要传送
Ratchet, we need a bridge.
需要传送的不只是你们
You are not the only ones.
一切回归正常
Everything's back to normal.
至少大黄蜂复原了
Well, normal for Bumblebee.
没关系
It's OK.
我当然很勇敢
Of course I was.
我理解
I know.
他说什么？
What did he say?
他说谢谢
He said thanks.